<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on Sophia A. McClennen</title><link>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on Sophia A. McClennen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 13:52:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pranksters vs. Autocrats</title><link>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/pranksters-vs-autocrats/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/pranksters-vs-autocrats/</guid><description>Do you want to overthrow a dictator, expose political corruption, or advance democratic goals? Pranksters vs. Autocrats presents a proven method to help advance the goals of non-violent activists. We offer in-depth analysis and a how-to guide to dilemma actions – a tactic that helps put political opponents in a lose-lose situation and gain visibility for your movement. Non-violent activists have long known that dilemma actions are especially effective, but this is the first book to offer empirical data to prove how and why dilemma actions work.</description></item><item><title>Globalization and Latin American Cinema: Towards a New Critical Paradigm</title><link>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/2-globalization-and-latin-american-cinema-towards-a-new-critical-paradigm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/2-globalization-and-latin-american-cinema-towards-a-new-critical-paradigm/</guid><description>Studying the case of Latin American cinema, this book analyzes one of the most public - and most exportable- forms of postcolonial national culture to argue that millennial era globalization demands entirely new frameworks for thinking about the relationship between politics, culture, and economic policies. Concerns that globalization would bring the downfall of national culture were common in the 1990s as economies across the globe began implementing neoliberal, free market policies and abolishing state protections for culture industries.</description></item><item><title>The Routledge Companion to Human Rights and Literature</title><link>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/the-routledge-companion-to-human-rights-and-literature/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/the-routledge-companion-to-human-rights-and-literature/</guid><description>The Routledge Companion to Literature and Human Rights provides a comprehensive, transnational, and interdisciplinary map to this emerging field, offering a broad overview of human rights and literature while providing innovative readings on key topics. The first of its kind, this volume covers essential issues and themes, necessarily crossing disciplines between the social sciences and humanities. Sections cover:
subjects, with pieces on subjectivity, humanity, identity, gender, universality, the particular, the body forms, visiting the different ways human rights stories are crafted and formed via the literary, the visual, the performative, and the oral contexts, tracing the development of the literature over time and in relation to specific regions and historical events impacts, considering the power and limits of human rights literature, rhetoric, and visual culture Drawn from many different global contexts, the essays offer an ideal introduction for those approaching the study of literature and human rights for the first time, looking for new insights and interdisciplinary perspectives, or interested in new directions for future scholarship.</description></item><item><title>The Debt Age</title><link>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/the-debt-age/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/the-debt-age/</guid><description>This collection of essays, by some of the most distinguished public intellectuals and cultural critics in America explores various dimensions of what it means to live in the age of debt. They ask, what is the debt age? For that matter, what is debt? Is its meaning transhistorical or transcultural? Or is it imbued in ideology and thus historically contingent? What is the relationship between debt and theory? Whose debt is acknowledged and whose is ignored?</description></item><item><title>Is Satire Saving Our Nation?</title><link>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/is-satire-saving-our-nation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/is-satire-saving-our-nation/</guid><description>Do you watch satire TV? Have you re-posted a hilarious, yet biting graphic on facebook or tweeted round the clock jabs at inane politicians? Does it sometimes seem to you that Jon Stewart is a better journalist than most of CNN, Fox, and MSNBC? And were you a bit disappointed when Stephen Colbert did not actually run for president? If you or someone you know has done any of the above, then you&amp;rsquo;ll want to read this book.</description></item><item><title>The Generation of &amp;#8217;72</title><link>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/the-generation-of-72/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/the-generation-of-72/</guid><description>Caught between the well-worn grooves the Boom and the Gen-X have left on the Latin American literary canon, the writing intellectuals that comprise what the Generation of &amp;lsquo;72 have not enjoyed the same editorial acclaim or philological framing as the literary cohorts that bookend them. In sociopolitical terms, they neither fed into the Cold War-inflected literary prizes that sustained the Boom nor the surge in cultural capital in Latin American cities from which the writers associated with the Crack and McOndo have tended to write.</description></item><item><title>The Dialectics of Exile</title><link>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/the-dialectics-of-exile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/the-dialectics-of-exile/</guid><description>The history of exile literature is as old as the history of writing itself. Despite this vast and varied literary tradition, criticism of exile writing has tended to analyze these works according to a binary logic, where exile either produces creative freedom or it traps the writer in restrictive nostalgia. The Dialectics of Exile: Nation, Time, Language, and Space in Hispanic Literatures offers a theory of exile writing that accounts for the persistence of these dual impulses and for the ways that they often co-exist within the same literary works.</description></item><item><title>Colbert&amp;#8217;s America</title><link>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/colberts-america/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/colberts-america/</guid><description>In 2005, comedian Stephen Colbert left the cast of The Daily Show for his own show, The Colbert Report, which has since become famous for satirizing personality-driven political shows like The O’Reilly Factor and Hannity. Since the show’s first episode, Colbert’s program has entertained its audience, encouraged political discourse, and stirred some of the most complacent members of society.
In her new book Colbert’s America: Satire and Democracy, Penn State professor, Sophia A.</description></item><item><title>Neoliberalism, Education, Terrorism</title><link>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/neoliberalism-education-terrorism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/neoliberalism-education-terrorism/</guid><description>Neoliberalism, Education, Terrorism: Contemporary Dialogues is a collaborative effort among four established public intellectuals who deeply care about the future of education in America and who are concerned about the dangerous effects of neoliberalism on American society and culture. It aims to provide a clear, concise, and thought-provoking account of the problems facing education in America under the dual shadows of neoliberalism and terrorism. Through collaborative and individual essays, the authors provide a provocative account that will be of interest to anyone who concerning with the opportunities and dangers facing the future of education at this critical moment in history.</description></item><item><title>America According to Colbert</title><link>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/america-according-to-colbert/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/america-according-to-colbert/</guid><description>Is the comedy of Stephen Colbert simply fun or is it powerful political satire? Does it entertain viewers or does it empower them? Or does it teach us that in today’s media-saturated world those binaries make no sense? America According to Colbert: Satire as Public Pedagogy claims that Colbert’s satire fosters critical thinking about social issues, encourages active citizenship, and entertains the viewer—all at the same time. The first book to cover the various themes and features of The Colbert Report, America According to Colbert offers readers insight into the powerful ways that Colbert’s comedy challenges the cult of ignorance that has threatened meaningful public debate and social dialogue since 9/11.</description></item><item><title>Representing Humanity in an Age of Terror</title><link>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/representing-humanity-in-an-age-of-terror-needs-cover/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/representing-humanity-in-an-age-of-terror-needs-cover/</guid><description>Written in the context of critical dialogues about the war on terror and the global crisis in human rights violations, authors of the collected volume Representing Humanity in an Age of Terror, edited by Sophia A. McClennen and Henry James Morello, ask a series of questions: What definitions of humanity account for the persistence of human rights violations? How do we define terror and how do we understand the ways that terror affects the representation of those that both suffer and profit from it?</description></item><item><title>Ariel Dorfman</title><link>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/ariel-dorfman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/ariel-dorfman/</guid><description>Ariel Dorfman: An Aesthetics of Hope is a critical introduction to the life and work of the internationally renowned writer, activist, and intellectual Ariel Dorfman. It is the first book about the author in English and the first in any language to address the full range of his writing to date. Consistently challenging assumptions and refusing preconceived categories, Dorfman has published in every major literary genre (novel, short story, poetry, drama); adopted literary forms including the picaresque, epic, noir, and theater of the absurd; and produced a vast amount of cultural criticism.</description></item><item><title>Comparative Cultural Studies and Latin America</title><link>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/comparative-cultural-studies-and-latin-america-needs-cover/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2004 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sophiamcclennen.com/book/comparative-cultural-studies-and-latin-america-needs-cover/</guid><description>This volume’s genesis stems from the contributors’ conviction that, given its vitality and excellence, Latin American literature deserves a more prominent place in comparative literature publications, curricula, and disciplinary discussions. The editors introduce the volume arguing, first, that there still exists, in some quarters, a lingering bias against literature written in Spanish and Portuguese and, second, that by embracing Latin American literature and culture more enthusiastically, comparative literature would find itself reinvigorated, placed into productive discourse with a host of issues, languages, literatures, and cultures that have too long been paid scant academic attention.</description></item></channel></rss>